Zoya Matsiy DataAnalyst

Milan, Italy +39 345-322-1343 zoyany39@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Tableau Public</u> <u>Github</u>

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A motivated and team-work-oriented analyst with 10+ years of experience in the Wholesale Trade, Tourism, and Real Estate Sector and 20+ years of relevant experience. Specializing in transforming raw big-size data into valuable information through reports and presentations to support data-driven decision-making and marketing and sales strategy definition.

GOAI

Enhance original sales data analysis algorithm. Achieve a higher level of professional excellence in statistical modeling,

Become a leader in the field of data analysis.

SKILLS

- Business Analytics
- Excel ninja
- Data visualization with **Tableau**
- PostgreSQL
- Python libraries and dashboards (NumPy, Pandas, SciPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, Scikit-Learn)
- Statistical and predictive analysis
- Data modeling (ARIMA model) and forecasting

COMPETENCES

- Self-starter
- Accuracy and attention to detail
- **Critical and creative** thinking
- Presentation skills
- Stakeholder comunication
- Constant learner with a steep learning curve
- Effective **problem-solving** abilities
- Domain knowledge in finance, healthcare, e-commerce, wholesale

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Data Analytics Program

2024 - Career Foundry GmbH, Berlin, Germany MTSM - Master of Tourism Sales

Management

2014 - Bicocca University, Milan, Italy

MBA- Master of Business Administration

2000 - Otto von Guerike University, Magdeburg, Germany

LANGUAGES

English (fluent), Italian (fluent), Russian (native), German (advanced)

PROJECT EXAMPLE

Connecticut Real Estate Sales Data Analysis (Tableau, GirHub) December 2023

Description: The complex data analysis of Connecticut Real Estate sales to define the more profitable property clusters for **real estate investors** by using the **CRISP-DM** methodology and **Machine Learning** (ARIMA model)

Developed strategy:

- **Target clusters** for high-value investments.
- Align deals with **peak** summer and vear-end activity.
- Diversify your portfolio for **risk mitigation**.
- Explore Single-Family Houses at \$250,000 for **liquidity**
- Rely on the **ARIMA** model for accurate **forecasting** of future investment possibilities

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst/ MC immobiliare di Carrus (Milam, Italy)

Settembre 2018 - February 2020

Achievement: Thanks to regular reporting to stakeholders, increasing customer loyalty to 8%

- Build a **financial model** tailored to different real estate markets.
- Supportet customers **creating blueprints** of real estate investments with requested financial metrics

Business Consultant/4U Service (Milan, Italy)

July 2017 - Settembre 2018

Achievement: IT Company **diversification support**. Diversification completed in 4 months.

- Provided **Business Data Analytics** for diversification strategy definition.
- Created a Marketing plan of diversification and supported its realization.
- Provided Business Analytics for critical clients to continue collaboration. **98%** of the customers remained after diversification, with **10%** of customers growing after six months.

Business Data Analyst/Suend di TSM Tourism & Services Management srl (Milan, Italy)

June 2016 - July 2017

Achievement: The 20% expansion of the geographical area of tourism services thanks to creating the new relational database.

- Collect data and create a regional customers and accommodation services relational database (Eastern Europe).
- Regular Data Analytic **reporting** of the actual market situation, **KPI tracking panel** for providing services.

Director of Business Development/ Elkotex OAO (Moscow, Russia)

February 2001 – June 2012

Achievement: Thanks to data-driven decision-making, the total revenue of the enterprise increased by 22%. An effective sales team was created, and a new warehouse management system based on the new CRM was implemented. The system of regular reporting on a KPI basis was introduced.

- Total cost of wholesale textiles decreased by 5%.
- Total revenue of wholesale textiles increased by 8%
- The wholesale assortment changed by 32%, the total assortment increased by 57%
- The warehouse balances have been destroyed by 24%

Marketing and Sales Director/International Textile Group OAO (Moscow, Russia)

February 1999 - February 2001

Achievement: Thanks to effective Business Management, the total revenue of the enterprise increased by 12%. and digital sales accounting, including a new CRM, was implemented. The system of regular reporting on a KPI basis was introduced.

- Total sale costs decreased by 6%.
- Total revenue of wholesale textiles increased by 12%
- The total assortment increased by 10%
- The warehouse balances have been destroyed by 33%
- The customer's loyalty increased by 30%
- The warehouse balances have been destroyed by 24%

Marketing and Sales Director/Jonas Lebensmittelhandels GmbH (Moscow, Russia)

March 1999 - Octobre 2001

Achievement: Crisis Management after Crisis 1998. Launching of energetic beverage Start-up (Power Horse trademark) based on Data Analysis of actual market statement. Business Planning and Business Management. New sales department with positive profit after 4 months deployment.

- Staff selection and team building. Effective sales department deployment in 2 months.
- Developing a sales network in 4 months. The monthly increase in turnover by 25%.
- Marketing activity planning and management. Achievement of brand awareness in the region of Moscow in 4 months.